## Hector Rodriguez Ochoa

(253) 226-6091 omarodoch@outlook.com 19414 73rd Avenue E Spanaway, WA 98387

#### IT Professional

I consider myself an honest, and passionate IT Professional. With over 15 years of combined experience in providing a reliable source of solutions to everyday problems.

I believe that communication and service make a key role with clients, staff members, and other professionals in various areas across different job levels. Over the years I have demonstrated professional abilities in project management, budgeting, networking, critical thinking, analysis, troubleshooting, planning, communication, organization, training, and problem solving. I consider my work and my commitment a contribution to the company success.

- ➤ Patient and good listener
- Hardware & Software Management
- ▼ Efficient Communicator & Scheduler
- Skillful in Organization & Multitasking
- ▼ Task & Detail-Oriented
- **▼** Resourceful/Creative Problem Solver

### Professional Experience

# CompuCom Systems Inc. Field Engineer I

April 2020 – Present Tacoma/Olympia/Seattle

- Support over 50 local customer sites, traveling from site to site as assigned by a ticketing system including: Target, HomeDepot, 7-11, Chick-fil-A, T-Mobile, Ulta Beauty.
- **▼** Customer focus meeting deadlines and service level agreements (SLAs).
- ➤ A variety of Projects to attend specific client needs, including: IMACs, Multidisciplinary Team Coordination, On site surveys and diagnostics, data wiping.
- Supports user account information including rights, security and systems groups.
- Service and repair of networking components.
- Identified and repairs product failures, orders and replaces parts as needed.
- Submit detailed work notes, update records, submit orders on a daily basis.
- Maintain a high level of professionalism in a fast paced and demanding environment.
- Warranty service repair for: HP Workstations and Servers, Dell Workstations and Servers Lenovo Workstations and laptops and Lexmark Printers.
- Spare parts inventory management.
- On call duty rotations every 3 weeks.

#### Support and Repair Technician

Tacoma/Olympia/Seattle

- (Staffing agency) Strategic Systems, Dublin OH (1-855-717-4774)
- (Staffing Agency) Insight Global, Atlanta, GA (404-257-7900)
- (Staffing Agency) Kforce, Bellevue, WA (425-803-7100)
- Use of ticketing system (Zendesk, Spiceworks, ServiceNow) to keep track of the cases.
- ▼ Installed, maintained, and repair of hardware and software.
- Migrated data from old stations to new stations
- Remote support to clients via phone, email and remote desktop.
- ➤ Performed hardware refurbishment and resale.
- Migration from Windows 7 to Windows 10.
- Wireless and wired network setup diagnostics and repairs.
- Everyday interaction with clients helping them to solve computer related issues.
- ➤ Helped clients to solve problems related to computer use on a daily base such as: Data recovery, virus cleaning, reinstall windows, update drivers and OS.
- Writing of daily reports of progress, measures and actions taken and problems solved.

**SOECO S. de R.L.** 2015 – 2018

#### **IT Support Specialist**

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

- Assumed responsibility for server administration, maintenance and repair of accounting software and office computers, and training of new personal.
- Set up and management of Cloud services, (Office 365, Azure, Storage services)
- ➤ Facilitated licensing of software and managed the budget for new equipment; directed and coordinated the development of custom need software.
- Maintained computer networks and related computing environments, which included computer hardware, systems software, and all configurations.
- ➤ Implemented network security measures in order to protect data, software, and hardware; performed data backups and/or disaster recovery operations.
- ▼ Implemented changes to improve systems and network configurations and determined hardware or software requirements related to such changes.

#### Soluciones Tecnologicas Integrales (STI)

2010 - 2014

#### Junior Developer / Support and Repair Technician

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

- ➤ Performed computer assembly, repair, and diagnostics, and provided exceptional support to users via remote connection, telephone, as well as on-site.
- Analyzed, designed, and developed software, websites (Joomla! WordPress, HTML), and databases; interpreted software and hardware requirements.
- ➤ Handled/coordinated the diagnostics, design, installation, and maintenance of networks (wireless and wired) and servers (workgroups and domains).
- Created and distributed guides and manuals for software usage; provided training and instruction for users about software usage and troubleshooting.
- ➤ Managed and supervised multidisciplinary work teams (software and hardware); monitored and maintained the inventory of software and/or hardware.
- Daily use of CRM software keeping track of the evolution of every case.

#### Maintenance and Repair Technician

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

- Installed, maintained and performed minor repairs to hardware, software, and peripheral equipment, following design and/or installation specifications.
- Oversaw the daily performance of computer systems; set up equipment and ensured proper installation of hardware, operating systems, antivirus and all the basic needs of the user.
- Maintained accurate and complete records of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial action taken, and installation activities.
- ➤ Studied technical manuals, conferred with users, and conducted computer diagnostics to investigate/resolve problems, and to provide technical support.
- X Keep a high level of communication with clients to ensure the problems are resolved.

#### Education & Technical Skills

Computer Science Engineer, Catholic University of Honduras, Our Lady Queen of Peace, 2011

Computer Technician Certification, "Modelo" High School, Tegucigalpa, Honduras, 2003

▼ Hardware - Desktop PCs, Laptops, accessories; Security Cameras (Wired/Wireless), Routers, Switch, printers, scanners 

■ Setup of Network Terminals and Services – Windows OS (95, 98, ME, 2000, XP, Vista, 7, 8, 8.1,10); Mac OS (9, X); Linux (Ubuntu); Automatic Network Backups; Network Privilege; Network Resources (Folders, Printers, Scanners, Accounts, Access, Hard Drive, and Backups Usage, Endpoint Security); Remote Access; Routers, Access Points, Bridges, and Repeaters; Firewalls **X Software** – Operating System (Windows, Mac, Linux); Microsoft Office Suite; POP and IMAP Mail Accounts; Antivirus and Antispyware Software; Firewalls Software; Hardware Diagnostic Software; Backup Software; Data Recovery Software; Remote Access Software; Performance Optimizer Software; Virtualization Software (VMware) \* Software **Development** – Visual Basic, C# (6.0, .NET 2005, 2008, 2010, 2012, 2013, 2016, 2018); Joomla! (Templates, Modules, Extensions, Plugins); WordPress (Templates, Modules, Extensions, Plugins); Microsoft Access (XP, 2003, 2007, 2010, 2013); Microsoft SQL (2000, 2005, 2008, 2012) (Express, Personal, Professional, Server); Cristal Reports (8, 9, 10, 11, 2008, 2011); CASE Tools (ERwin, Embarcadero, DBartisan, Visio) **▼ Server Software** – Cloud Services; Office 365 services, AZURE, Active Directory, DHCP, DNS Microsoft Teams, Windows 2008 Server, Windows 2012 Server; Windows 2016 Server; Server Web Servers (Linux)

Language Skills: English **x** Spanish